# MARIA DEL PILAR DOMINGUEZ MOLINA

## COMPUTER SCIENCE STUDENT

Driven Data Science and Web Developer Intern with experience in web-based applications. Participated in the development and implementation of web-based solutions. Ready to combine tireless hunger for new skills with the desire to exploit data science and web technology.

# Contact

#### Address

Boston, MA, 02215

#### Phone

857-419-9128

#### E-mail

pilymdm@bu.edu

#### Website

https://pily01.github.io/ personal-website/#home

# **Coding Languages**

Python
Javascript
Java
C

#### Skills

Spanish native speaker

Fast Learner

Adaptability

Self motivation

Interpersonal communication

Teamwork

### **Interests**

C# Unity Game Development

Analysis of algorithms

Graph theory

Japanese language

# **Work History**

#### 2022-09-Current

#### Data Science Intern

MyStockDNA, Remote

- Created data visualization graphics, translating complex data sets into comprehensive visual representations.
- Completing Python for Data Science and Machine learning course to advance skills.
- Collaborated with business partners to understand business objectives.
- Mentored by Senior Data Science Developers, learning multiple systems and efficient development techniques.

#### 2022-06-Current

# Full Stack Web Developer Intern

deep\_dive, Mexico City, Mexico

- Developed, coded, modified, and debugged 2 web applications of varying degrees of complexity with full independence.
- Learned new emerging technologies such as OpenAI API and React, and took the initiative to offer technical direction and creative solutions.
- Worked with senior developers and designers to develop product landing page using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Cultivated good working relationships with strategic partners and internal teams.

# **Education**

#### 2017-09-Current

## Bachelor of Arts: Computer Science

Boston University - Boston MA

- Dean's List Spring Semester 2018
- Dean's List Spring Semester 2019
- Member of Hack4Impact

#### 2017-09-Current

# Study Abroad: Computer Science

Tecnologico de Monterrey TEC - Mexico City, Mexico

- Tutored First Year Computer Science students
- Member of SATI: Students In Internet Technologies

#### 2018-10 -2019-01

# **Bootcamp: Computer Science**

Ironhack - Mexico City, Mexico

- Awarded First Place in MERN Web Application Competition
- Awarded First Place in Javascript Game Development Competition